测试需要有正确的态度。
Testing requires having the right attitude.
所以当你在编码的时候，你的目标是让程序工作。
So when you're coding, your goal is to make the program work.
但是当你在测试的时候，当你在写测试的时候，
But when you're testing, when you're writing tests,
目标实际上是让它失败。
the goal is actually to make it fail.
最好的测试是找到一个bug。
The best kind of test is one that finds a bug.
这是一个微妙的，但却是非常重要的区别
This is a subtle, but is really important difference
因为如果你像个程序员一样思考
because if you're thinking like a coder
当你写测试的时候
when you're writing your tests, then it's
会很容易把代码当作
going to be tempting to treat that code as being
一件珍贵的东西
a precious thing and tested very likely
这样你就可以得到工作的回报
so you can get the reward of seeing it work
而不是残忍的挥舞着大锤，
rather than being brutal, wielding a sledgehammer,
到处打那东西
and beating on that thing everywhere
它可能很脆弱，所以你可以找到虫子
it might be vulnerable so that you can find the bugs
把他们弄出去。
and get them out of there.
所以你想摘下你的编码帽
So you want to take off your coder hat
戴上你的测试帽。
and put on your tester hat.
现在，有一个策略叫做测试优先编程。
Now, there's a strategy for this called test first programming.
测试优先编程的好处是
And the good thing about test first programming
直到最后才离开测试
is that it's not leaving testing until the end, when
你有一大堆代码
you have a giant pile of code and you don't really
想测试一下。
want to have to test it.
错误可能在代码中的任何地方。
And the bugs might be anywhere in that code.
最好是循序渐进，
It's much better to do it incrementally,
编写测试并在开发代码时运行它们。
to write tests and run them as you're developing your code.
实际上，在测试优先编程中，
In fact, in test first programming,
我们的想法是在
the idea is to write the test before you've
写任何实现。
written any implementation.
所以对于一个特殊的函数，你
So for a particular function, you
会先写一个规范
would first write a specification
对于该函数，规范描述了
for that function, where the specification describes
函数的输入和输出行为。
the input and output behavior of the function.
我们将进一步讨论规格
And we'll talk much more about specifications
在未来的课堂上。
in a future class.
基本上，它描述了函数应该做什么。
Basically, it describes what the function is supposed to do.
然后使用那个规范，
And then using that specification,
但在我们真正编写函数之前，
but before we've actually written the function,
编写调用该函数的测试
you write tests that call that function
确保它做了它应该做的
and make sure that it's doing what it should
根据你写的说明书。
according to the spec that you wrote.
然后你做的第三件事是
And then the third thing you do is
去写那个函数的实际主体。
to go and write the actual body of that function.
当你写的时候，你有测试用例
And while you're writing it, you have test cases
你可以一直跑直到他们
that you can be continuously running until they all
变绿。
turn green.
一旦你的代码通过了所有的测试，
And once your code passes all those tests,
那你就知道你完了。
then you know you're done.
按下J单元上的按钮会让人非常满意，
And it can be very satisfying to push the button on J-unit,
看到你所有的测试都是绿色的，知道你已经完成了
see all of your test be green, and know that you're done
你可以继续做下一件你必须做的事情。
and you can move on to the next thing that you have to build.
所以在这堂课的习题中，
So in the problem sets for this class,
我们要按照这个程序，这个测试
we're going to follow this procedure, this test
第一个编程过程。
first programming procedure.
事实上，在第一个问题集中
And in fact, in the first problem set
我们会给你规格和测试。
we're going to give you the specification and the tests.
你要写代码。
And you're going to write the code.
你会有在J单元上玩的经验
And you'll get that experience of pushing play on J-unit
看到你所有的测试都变绿了
and seeing all of your tests turn green
这是多么值得。
and how rewarding that is.
那我们给你一个问题集
Then we'll give you a problem set
我们给你规格的地方。
where we give you the specs.
但这些测试是你自己写的。
But it's up to you to write these tests.
我们会鼓励你先测试一下
And we'll encourage you to do it in a test first way
并实现该功能。
and to implement the function.
然后我们会有一个问题集
And then we'll have a problem set where basically all of this
是你的责任。
is your responsibility.
你应该先写规格再写测试，
You should write the specs first and write the tests,
然后编写实际的代码。
and then write the actual code.
从这个测试优先编程中获得的另一个优势
One other advantage you get from this test first programming
方法是写测试
methodology is that writing the test
首先帮助您理解规范。
first helps you understand the specification.
你实际上是这个规格的客户。
You're actually acting like a client for this spec.
您正在编写调用函数的测试。
You're writing tests that are calling the function.
这有助于调试规范。
And that helps you debug the spec.
它可以帮助你发现什么是模棱两可的，或者不完整的，
It helps you find out what is ambiguous, or incomplete,
或规格中缺少。
or missing from the specification.
所以在实际实现之前编写这些测试
So by writing those tests before you've actually implemented
这个规范，你正在解决一些错误
that specification, you're working out some of those bugs
在你把这个bug实现到规范之前，你已经是规范了。
in you're spec before you bother implementing that bug to spec.
所以现在让我们开始思考
So now let's turn to thinking about how we're going
选择这些测试用例。
to choose these test cases.
创建好的测试实际上是一个有趣的设计问题。
Creating good tests actually is an interesting design problem.
我们想做一组测试用例
We want to make a set of test cases
小到可以跑得很快
that's small enough to run quickly
但足够大给我们信心
but large enough to give us confidence
程序是有效的。
that the program is valid.
我们在2005年讨论的策略是
And the strategy we talked about in 005 is to divide the input
把函数空间分成子域，分成部分，
space of the function into sub-domains, into parts,
每个由一组输入组成。
each consisting of a set of inputs.
所以其中一件是一整套
So one of these things here is a whole set
可能的功能输入。
of possible inputs to the function.
综合起来，这些子域
And taken together, these sub-domains completely
覆盖输入空间。
cover the input space.
所以每个输入至少存在于这些部分中的一个。
So every input lies in at least one of these parts.
然后对于我们的测试套件，我们选择一个测试用例
And then for our test suite, we pick one test case
从每一个子域。
from each of these sub-domains.
子域背后的思想是
And the idea behind sub-domains is
我们想把输入空间分成几组
we want to partition the input space into sets
类似的投入。
of similar inputs.
所以在这个子域的所有输入上，
So on all of the inputs in this sub-domain,
程序应该有类似的行为
the program should have similar behavior
所以我们选择了一个有代表性的测试用例
so that this one representative test case we've chosen
可能与所有其他输入行为相似
is likely to behave similarly to all the other inputs
在那个子域中。
in that sub-domain.
所以这种系统化的方法是一个好方法
So this systematic approach is a good way
利用我们有限的测试资源。
to make use of our limited testing resources.
我们不想写大量的测试
We don't want to write tests for lots
在这个空间里多余的地方--
of redundant places in this space--
让我们选择输入空间的测试用例
let's us choose test cases that are input space
如果我们只是随便挑选测试，或者
that if we were just picking tests haphazardly, or picking
他们是随机的，我们甚至可能都够不着。
them randomly, we might not even reach.
让我们看两个例子。
Let's look at two examples.
所以首先，大整数乘法。
So first of all, big integer multiply.
Big integer是一个内置在Java库中的类。
Big integer is a class that's built into the Java library.
它表示任意精度的整数，
And it represents arbitrary precision integers,
换句话说，整数可以
in other words, integers that can get
你需要多大就多大。
as big as you needed to get.
不同于int和long的原始类型，
Unlike the primitive types int and long,
范围有限
that have limited ranges, that have
它们可以表示的最大值集，
maximum value set they can represent,
大整数可以表示任何
big integer can represent anything
你的记忆可以保存。
that your memory can possibly hold.
大整数有乘法的方法。
Big integer has a method multiply.
乘法的目的是把两个大整数相乘
And the purpose of multiply is to multiply two big integer
共同的价值观。
values together.
所以它需要一个大的整数值。
So it takes a big integer value.
因为它是一个实例方法，
And because it's an instance method,
它需要这个，这就是它被召唤的原因。
it takes this, which is what it's being called on.
它返回一个新的大整数
And it returns a new big integer that
是调用该方法的对象的乘积
is the product of this object that the method is called on
以及传递给它的值。
and the value passed into it.
例如，你可能有一个大整数a，
For example, you might have a big integer A,
你初始化成一个大整数
that you initialized to something big integer
B、 然后产品A，B会
B. And then the product A, B would
是一个点乘以B。所以这个例子
be A dot multiplied B. So this example
表明即使只有一个
shows that even though there's only one
方法声明中的显式参数，multiply，
explicit parameter here in the method declaration, multiply,
把它看作一个数学函数
thinking about it as a mathematical function actually
有两个论点。
has two arguments.
它是你调用方法的对象，然后
It's the object that you're calling the method on and then
传递它的参数。
the parameter that you're passing it.
在Python中，接收方法调用的对象
In Python, the object receiving the method call
将在方法中显式命名为参数。
will be explicitly named as a parameter here in the method.
它将被称为自我。
It will be called self.
Java，你没说。
Java, you don't mention that.
它隐含在这个方法声明中。
And it's implicit in this method declaration.
它恰好被称为这个而不是细胞。
And it happens to be called this instead of cells.
这就是Java和Python之间的区别。
So those are differences between Java and Python.
但是从测试和分区的角度来看
But from the point of view of testing, and partitioning
子域中的空间，我们应该
the space in the sub domains, we should
把乘法看作一个接受两个输入的函数，
think of multiply as a function taking two inputs,
它们中的每一个都是大整数类型，也会产生一个输出
each of them of type big integer producing one output also
大整数类型的。
of type big integers.
所以它是两个参数和一个返回的函数。
So it's a function of the two arguments and one return.
所以我们有一个二维输入空间
So we have a two-dimensional input space consisting
所有整数对中的A，B。现在我们对它进行分区。
of all the pairs of integers A, B. Now let's partition it.
所以想想乘法
So thinking about how multiplication
作品与乘法的各种情况
works and the different kinds of cases of multiplication
你可能在学校学到的，
that you might have learned about in school,
我们可以从这些分区开始。
we might start with these partitions.
首先，A和B都是阳性，
First, A and B are both positive,
这应该会给我们一个积极的结果。
which should give us a positive result.
第二，A和B都是阴性的，
Second, A and B are both negative,
我们必须小心
where we have to be careful and make
我们肯定会有好结果的。第二，A
sure we get a positive result. Second, A
是正的，B是负的，A和负的，B是正的。
is positive B is negative, A and negative, B is positive.
所以这是四个合理的分区
So those are four reasonable partitions
对于乘法运算。
for the multiply operation.
请注意，我们考虑过当
And notice that we thought about how multiply works when
决定那些分区。
deciding on those partitions.
还有一些特殊情况
There are also some special cases
对于乘法，我们应该检查特定的值。
for multiplication, particular values that we should check.
0，它总是应该产生0，
0, which is always supposed to produce 0,
1，这应该是身份——它应该总是
1, which is supposed to be the identity-- it should always
产生与之相乘的另一个值--
produce the other value that you're multiplying it with--
负1，就像负身份一样。
and negative 1, which is like the negative identity.
最后，作为一个可疑的测试者
And finally, as the suspicious tester
他在想会发生什么
who's thinking about what might go
在这些实现中是错误的，用大锤敲打它，
wrong in these implementations, beating it with a sledgehammer,
我们可能会想，好吧，也许大整数的实现者
we might think, well, maybe the implementer of big integer
试图通过使用
is trying to make it faster by using
尽可能在内部使用这些原始整数之一
one of these primitive integers internally whenever possible
只会回到一个昂贵的将军身边
and only falling back to an expensive general
表示法，例如，一个数字列表
representation, like, say, a list of digits
当值变得太大时。
when the value gets too big.
所以我们也应该试试大的，大的整数
So we should also try integers that are very big, bigger
比最大的长。
than the biggest long.
这给了我们一种不同的划分。
And this gives us a different kind of partition.
所以A或B是一个小整数，足够小
So A or B is a small integer, one small enough
适合于一个整数或长整数。
to fit into an int or a long.
顺便说一句，这仍然是一个很大的限制。
That's still, by the way, a pretty big limit.
另一方面，A或B的绝对值
The other way, the absolute value of A or B
比你能装进原语的还要大。
is bigger than you can fit into a primitive.
长点最大值实际上会给你
Long dot max value will actually give you
Java中最大的可能原始整数。
the biggest possible primitive integer in Java.
大约是63的2倍。
And it's roughly 2 to the 63 power.
所以我们想做个实验。
So we would like to experiment.
我们想做一些测试，测试A和B的大值
We'd like to have tests that try big values of A and B
为了确保我们真的
in order to make sure that we really
使用大整数的方式。
are using big integers the way they can be used.
所以让我们把这些观察结果
So let's bring all of these observations
一起形成一个简单的分区
together into a straightforward partition
整个二维A，B空间。
of the whole two-dimensional A, B space.
所以我们要从这些部分中独立选择A和B。
So we're going to choose A and B independently from these parts.
看看这里很有用。
And it's useful to look at it over here.
我们把A区域分成了很多负数，
We've split up the A range into large negative numbers,
小负数，负1，0，1，小正数，
small negative numbers, negative 1, 0, 1, small positive,
一个很大的积极因素。
and a large positive.
我们对B也做了同样的事。
And we've done the same thing with B.
这两个分区的乘积
And the product of those two partitions
给我们这些子域。
gives us these sub-domains.
所以这是一个子域，其中a是一个很大的负数
So this is a sub-domain in which A is a large negative number
B是一个很大的负数。
and B is a large negative number.
这里的每个点都是一个特殊的a，B对。
And each of the points in here is a particular A, B pair.
有了这些分区，我们最终
And with these partitions, we end up
整个A，B空间有49个分区
with 49 partitions of the entire A, B space that completely
覆盖整数空间。
cover the space of integers.
为了产生一个测试，我们需要选择一些测试用例，a，B，
To produce a test, we'd want to pick some test case, A, B,
从网格的每一个正方形。
from each square of the grid.
例如，从这个方格中
So for example, from this square of the grid
我们正在挑选一个a为负1的病例。
we're picking a case where A is negative 1.
B是一个很大的正数。
B is some large positive number.
让我们再看一个例子。
Let's look at another example.
所以考虑max函数
So consider the max function, which
将两个整数A和B转换为普通的、原始的、整数
takes two integers, A and B, to just ordinary, primitive, ints
现在，返回这两个的最大值，以
now, and returns the maximum value of those two, whichever
一个更大。
one is larger.
这是一个函数，它接受两个参数
This is a function that takes-- this is a two argument
功能。
function.
它告诉两个图像并产生另一个整数。
It tells two images and produces another integer.
从规格上看，这是有道理的
And from the spec, it makes sense
根据它的行为把它分成一个箱子。
to partition it into the case according to how it behaves.
所以如果A小于B
So if A is less than B, it's going
返回B.A等于B，
to be returning B. A is equal to B,
它可以返回其中任何一个。
it can return either one of them.
如果A大于B，它将返回A。
If A is greater than B it's going to be returning A.
所以有三种可能
So these are three different possible kinds
这个函数的行为。
of behavior for this function.
这给了我们三个不同的子域
And that gives us these three different sub-domains
在A，B空间。
in the A, B space.
在这种情况下，A更大--
This is the case where A is greater--
或者B大于A。对不起。
or B is greater than A. Sorry.
这是A等于B的线。
This is the line where A equals B.
这就是A大于B的地方。
And this is the place where A is greater than B.
所以我们的测试套件可以简单地选择一个测试用例
So our test suite might then simply pick a test case
从每一个子域。
from each of these sub-domains.
如果A等于1，B等于2，
So if A equals 1, and B equals 2,
包括A小于B的子域等等。
that covers the sub-domain where A is less than B and so forth.
现在，除了这些子域之外，
Now, in addition to these sub-domains,
考虑边界通常很重要
it's often important to think about the boundaries
在子域之间。
between sub-domains.
例如，0是正负之间的边界
For example, 0 is a boundary between positive and negative
数字。
numbers.
最大和最小可能值
The largest and smallest possible values
范围有限的类型，如int和double
of limited range types like int and double
是重要的界限。
are important boundaries.
当你有一个集合，比如一个数组，或者一个字符串，
When you have a collection, like an array, or a string,
或者一个列表，有了它，这个集合就空了
or a list, having that thing, that collection be empty
是一个重要的边界。
is an important boundary.
如果你说的函数
If you're talking about a function that
带着收藏品做点什么
takes a collection and does something
或者在收藏品里找东西，
or looks for something in the collection,
不管事情是在开始
then whether the thing is at the beginning
或者说收尾是一个重要的价值。
or the end of the collection is an important value.
我们都在考虑边界的一个原因
One reason we all think about boundaries
程序员经常在边界上犯错误。
is that programmers often make mistakes at boundaries.
他们经常犯一个错误，比如写不到
They often make off by one errors, like writing less than
或者等于他们应该写的少于，
or equal to where they should have written less than,
或者从1开始而不是从0开始。
or starting from 1 instead of 0.
另一个是有些界限可能
Another is that some boundaries may
必须由代码中的特殊情况处理，
have to be handled by special cases in the code,
或者它们可能是
or they may be places where there's
代码行为的不连续性。
a discontinuity in the code's behavior.
当整数变量溢出时
Turns out that when an integer variable overflows
当你试图达到一个比int更高的数时
when you try to reach a higher number than int
实际上可以代表，它突然
can actually represent, it abruptly
跳到一个负数。
jumps down to a negative number.
这是不连续的行为，不像正常的
And that's a discontinuous behavior, unlike normal
增量。
increment.
所以考虑这些界限很重要
So it's important to think about these boundaries
考虑把它们作为子域
and think about including them as sub-domains
在你的隔间里。
in your partition.
事实上，事实上，我们做到了，
So we did, actually, as it turns out,
这里有一些有用的边界，0，1和负1，
have some useful boundaries here, 0, 1, and negative 1,
是出于思考
were ones that came out of thinking
关于乘法的性质。
about the properties of multiplication.
但是也可以使用这个长点max
But it would also be useful to include this long dot max
作为实际边界条件的值，
value as an actual boundary case,
作为此分区中的实际附加子域。
as an actual additional sub-domain in this partition.
让我们也为麦克斯考虑一下。
Let's think about it for the max as well.
我们在某种意义上已经有了界限，
We did in a sense already have a boundary here,
这个地方介于A和A之间
this place between where A is less
比B大，A比B大，但我们也应该
than B and A is greater than B. But we should also
想想A的值是0，或者B的值
think about the values of A being 0, or the value of B
是0，这对分区也有什么影响，
being 0, and what that also does to the partitions,
它们之间的子域。
the sub-domains between them.
我们还应该考虑最小整数和最大
And we should also think about minimum integers and maximum
这里是整数，因为max函数可以
integers here because the max function may or may not
正确处理此问题。
work correctly on this.
然后我们，再次，选择测试用例
And then we, again, pick test cases
涵盖我们这里所有的课程。
to cover all of the classes that we have here.
现在，在我们将输入空间划分成子域之后，
Now, after we've partitioned the input space into sub-domains,
实际上我们还有一些设计选择
we actually still have some design choice
因为我们可以选择如何精疲力尽
here because we can choose how exhausted
我们希望测试套件是。
we want the test suite to be.
例如，在乘法例子中，
In, for example, the multiply example,
我们采取了所有的方法
we took the product of all the ways
我们分割了A，所有分割B的方法，
that we partitioned A, and all the ways that we partition B,
最后我们得到了49个子域。
and we ended up with 49 sub-domains.
我们为每个人挑选了一个测试用例
And we picked a test case for every single one
在这49个测试用例中。
of those 49 test cases.
所以这是一个详尽的方法。
So that's the exhaustive way of doing it.
这是完整的笛卡尔积，
That's the full Cartesian product,
每个单独参数部分的意义
the sense of the parts of each of the individual parameters
到函数。
to the function.
一种更轻量级的方法来考虑创建测试
A lighter weight way to think about creating the test
因为那是很多测试用例--
case because that's a lot of test cases--
49个测试用例是很多要选择的测试用例--
49 test cases is a lot of test cases to choose--
只是要确保我们在
is just make sure that we're covering
每个单独尺寸的每个部分
each part of each individual dimension
通过一些测试用例，但不一定是每个组合。
by some test case, but not necessarily every combination.
因此，使用这种方法，我们可以为max选择测试用例。
So with this approach, we might choose test case for max.
这是一个小型的S5测试用例。
It's a small S5 test cases.
事实上这就是我们在这里所做的选择，
And that is in fact the choice we made here,
保险范围是每一个
is coverage every single one of each
在这些个人选择中。
of these individual choices.
但它不能确定，例如，
But it doesn't make sure that, for example,
我们的每一个选择
for each of these choices of A we're
打在每一个可能的选择之间的关系
hitting every possible choice of the relationship between A
而且我们正在尽一切可能选择恋爱关系
and B and we're hitting every possible choice of relationship
我们经常罢工
of the value of B. So often we strike
基于我们的判断，在这些极端之间做出一些妥协，
some compromise between these extremes based on our judgment,
基于我们的谨慎程度，并在一定程度上影响了
based on our amount of caution, and influenced somewhat
通过白盒测试和代码覆盖率[？规则？]，其中
by white box testing and code coverage [? rules ?], which
我们下一步要看。
we're going to look at next.